Recently, I have been obsessed with
context engineering. I'll be the first
one to admit it. But it's for a good
reason. I've been pouring my heart and
soul into developing reliable and even
more importantly, repeatable ways to
give super robust context to LLM so we
can build anything. And what I want to
show you right now is what I've been
cooking up in the lab recently, working
on context engineering, but for building
AI agents in just minutes using
paidantic AI. And as a part of this
video, we'll even go through and use
this template to build an AI agent
together. Now, using AI coding
assistants to build AI agents should be
pretty straightforward. I mean, there's
a very standard way to define our
prompts and our tools and our
dependencies. But if you've ever tried
it yourself, you know, it is not that
simple. We can't just go into our
windsurf or our cursor or our kirao or
our cloud code or the millions of other
tools that we have right now for coding
and just say something like build me an
AI agent for customer support. I mean
you just know that this is not going to
cut it. I mean, you might get something
with this, but it's going to be more of
a demo that definitely breaks with real
users and real data, and you're probably
going to get stuck in the hell that
we've all had with AI coding assistants
at some point where we have just this
infinite loop of iterating on a few
problems. But the problem here is not
your AI coding assistant or LLM. It's
the context that you are providing. We
can't just vibe code and skip right to
implementation. We need an entire
planning phase up front to sharpen our
axe and give the context necessary for
the AI coding assistant to have what it
takes to plausibly oneshot the solution
effectively. And that is what context
engineering aims to solve and the
strategy that I've been focusing on a
lot recently is using Arasmus' PRP
framework that I've been talking about a
lot on my channel recently. And so I
have this template available for you
that I've covered on my channel and now
I have a specific version of it that is
hypertuned for building AI agents with
podantic AI. This is the focus of this
video here and it's going to be fun. Now
the PRP framework is just one way to
context engineer, but it is my favorite
by far and it's so straightforward
because we are using the AI coding
assistant in very strategic ways to help
us generate the context. That's the key.
And so going back to the root of the
repo here. It's just a three-step
process that we have to follow with the
PRP framework at a high level. So first
you have to edit a file to describe in
detail the application or in our case
the agent that we want to create and
then we take this initial MD and we use
the AI coding assistant to help us
expand that into a full what is called
product requirements prompt. It's like a
PRD if you're familiar with that, but
more specifically crafted to be a prompt
with extensive context to help the AI
coding assistant then build out our
feature when we execute the PRP. So very
simple three-step process. And the main
thing that we do here, if I go into the
PRP folder, we have this template for a
base PRP. So we essentially take this
combine it with our own feature
requirements in our initial MD and this
creates the full set of context that we
need that includes things like
documentation to reference the code
structure that we want at the end any
gotchas that we have best practices and
patterns for developing whatever we're
trying to develop. It's a very complete
set of context. And so the best part
with this is I can take this base PRP. I
can take the other parts that we have
here like our commands to generate and
execute PRPS and I can hyper tune these
to specific use cases. And that is
exactly what I've done here for Pantic
AI for you to be able to create AI
agents super easily. So, I'm just trying
to set the stage here and show you what
went into creating this because I spent
hours and hours pulling in my old Pantic
AI projects, doing research and finding
best practices, and then essentially
creating a PRP to create this template
for you. So, I used AI coding assistants
to help me build this as well. And so,
like for example, we have a base PRP,
but now hyper tuned to Pyantic AI. So, I
have like best practices and examples
and patterns built in for Pyantic AI
specifically. So now when you go through
that three-step process of describing
your agent and then generating the PRP
and executing it, it has all this
information for Padantic AI already
built into it. And this reduces
hallucination so so much. And I'm going
to keep doing this for other use cases
as well. Like I have this folder here. I
showed MCP servers in my last video. I'm
going to keep building more and more
just creating these super beautiful
starting points for you. So, you have to
spend hours and hours less context
engineering because I've already done it
for you. Like, I can take these
templates, give them to you, and you can
basically just like dive right into
creating your agent in just a couple of
minutes. It's that easy. And that's what
we're going to be doing in this video.
I'll show you how it works. And we'll
build an AI agent together that's not
actually that trivial. It's an agent
that can do web research and manage our
inbox, doing things like drafting emails
as well. So, this is what we're going to
create together. And I've actually
already built this with both Claude Code
and Curo before recording just to
validate this. And I also literally used
the template to build an agent to then
refine the template more like just
fixing up things that I didn't quite get
right. So yeah, trust me, I put a lot of
time into building this template for
you. And so that's enough of me talking
about it. I just want to like actually
dive in and build the agent out with you
now. All right. So I've got my repo
cloned locally. Now, we can dive into
building our AI agent with the PRP
framework and this template that I have
for you, which I'll have a link in the
description to this template and the
entire context engineering repo. This is
all open source and available for you.
And like I said, I'm going to keep
building out more use cases as well. In
fact, I'm going to be making this a
project in the Dynamis community. And
so, if you want to get way more involved
with AI coding and context engineering
and you want to be a part of an awesome
project, definitely check out
Dynamus.ai. We got a lot of awesome
stuff going on there for AI coding and
context engineering. But anyway, back to
our readme here. Let's go ahead and get
started getting ready to build our
agent. So, the first thing after you
clone this repository, we want to take
our Pantic AI template and we want to
copy it to a working directory
essentially where we're going to take
the template and build it into a
complete agent. And I've set it up this
way in case you want to reuse this
template many times. So, we have this
target directory where it's just going
to copy everything that we need for our
slash commands and our global rules and
our base PRP to wherever we want. And
so, within my terminal here, I'm just
running the copy template.pycript like
the readme says. And I'm going to have
everything copied over to this folder.
So, it's going to happen just like
pretty much instantaneously there. There
we go. We copied over all of our
examples. We have that initial MD that
we have to fill out. We have our base
PRP and then our slash commands. Which
by the way, if you're not using cloud
code, you can still use these slash
commands. You just basically in your
prompt to your AI coding assistant, tell
it to use the command as the prompt. And
I actually did that with Kira. I'll just
show you an example of this really
quick. I'm not building with Kira in
this video. I'm going to be building
with cloud code. But just to show you
that I've done this with other AI coding
assistants as well. And so you can see
my prompt. I literally told it
use.cloud/comand/ cloud/comand/execute
podantic AI PRP as your prompt and then
the argument because we have to pass in
the PRP that we want to execute. I just
give it the the name of that file as
well. And there we go. Kira goes ahead
and does all the implementation just
like we would see in cloud code. And it
did a phenomenal job by the way. Like
I'm very impressed with Kira as one of
the new up andcoming AI coding
assistants. Definitely let me know in
the comments if you want me to dive more
into Kira or other AI coding assistants.
But right now, Cloud Code is still my
primary driver. So, I'm going to be
focusing on that in this video. But
yeah, so we've got our new repository
set up. And so, I'm going to copy this
directory. I'm going to change into it.
And then I'll just open in my ID, which
I'm just using WinSurf here, but I open
up the terminal to use Cloud Code. So,
I'll I'll go ahead and do that right
now. So, I'll close Cascade. We're in a
terminal. I'm using Windows, so I'll go
to Ubuntu, so I can access Claude here.
All right. So, there we go. And then
what I want to show you really quickly
is what is copied over for this
template. So we have our claw.md. These
are our global rules that I've also
hyper tuned to building pideantic AI
agents. And you can read through all
this if you are curious the way that
I've specified you know like the general
file structure for agents best practices
for configuring environment variables
and how we set up the specific provider
and LLM that we want to use. There's a
lot of work that I put into this. And
then we have that podantic AI specific
base PRP. And then the main thing that I
want to start with here is our initial
MD because this is our first step. And
we're going to dive into this now. We're
going to set up all the requirements
around our agent and then generate the
PRP based on that. The sponsor of
today's video is Scribba, a platform
that turns coding tutorials into pair
programming sessions where you can
literally edit the instructor's code in
real time. And there are exercises that
are built right into the tutorials. It
really does revolutionize the way that
you learn how to code. And while AI can
help us code faster, like we're covering
in this video, it is still crucial for
you to understand the fundamentals, both
backend and front-end development. I
mean, there's a reason why I talk so
much about validation when I'm covering
the PRP framework. And Scribba recently
released their full stack developer
path. Over 100 hours of incredible
content taking you from beginner to pro
for both backend and front-end
development, so you can develop some of
the most in- demand tech skills in the
industry. So, just to show you really
quick how powerful and unique Scribba
is, take a look at this. So, I'm going
to play one of the videos here. And I
have the instructor muted, but he is
talking right now. He's moving his mouse
around on the screen. So, he's in the
middle of showing me something, but at
any point in the lesson, I can pause the
video. I can go to any of the files just
like I'm in a text editor on my local
computer and I can change anything like
I could say instead of add ingredients,
add food. I can do control S or run in
the top right. And there we go. Our
preview is updated live. So, we can
update to just tweak things and try
things out at any point during any
video. And then also there are these
challenges that we have throughout the
content where they explicitly will ask
us to implement something. So we really
are pair programming as a part of our
lessons. It's so powerful. It helps you
learn so fast. Also, Scribba has a lot
of other courses as well like these ones
that they offer for AI. They even
partnered with Mistl Hugging Face and
Cloudflare recently to bring these to
you guys. It's so cool. You also get AI
feedback on your code in all of your
courses. and they have a super
supportive community through Discord. So
really, Scribba is the place to go if
you want to level up your tech skills,
master what is in demand right now. So
I'll have a link in the description to
Scribba. I definitely recommend checking
them out. So first of all, when we build
an AI agent with Pideantic AI, and
really this is going to apply no matter
the framework you use. Agents generally
consist of three parts. And I'm just
showing the weather agent from their
documentation just to give you a highle
overview. This is why I crafted the
initial MD template in the way that I
did. So, first of all, our agents will
always have dependencies. These are
things that we need in our tools like
API keys, database connections. In this
case, we have an HTTP client that we
need to browse the internet. And then we
also have our agent definition itself.
This is the second component where we
have things like our system prompt. And
then last but not least, our agents
always have tools. These are functions
or MCP servers that we attach to our
agent so it can actually do things on
our behalf and that's usually most of
the implementation for our agents. So
those are the three components and
that's why I've crafted the initial MD
in this way because it's very important
to be specific to the AI coding
assistant when building agents what
you're looking for for those three
components. And so first of all at a
very high level we have our feature.
What is the AI agent that we want to
build? and you just want to replace
everything in brackets here in the
template. I have a really simple, like
super super simple example here as well.
You definitely want to be more detailed
than this, but this is just a starting
point for you. And then diving into the
exact tools that you want. Like for our
research agent, we want our agent to be
able to use, let's say, the Brave API to
browse the internet and summarize web
research. We want another sub agent to
manage our inbox and do things like
draft emails. Like, get specific for the
tools here. And after I walk through
this, I'll show you what my final
initial MD looks like as well. And then
for dependencies, again, things like API
keys and database connections for our
system prompt. You don't have to write
out the entire system prompt here, but
you can if you want. Otherwise, you can
just kind of generally describe what you
want in your system prompt to make sure
that you're steering your agents
correctly. And then what I generally
include for all of my PRP initial MD
templates is a section for examples. So
you could pull past projects that you've
worked on. Like I have a lot of Pantic
AI agents I've already built. So I have
some of these put in the example folder
already. So we kind of have a starting
point for examples. So you can just go
off of this if you want. And this could
also be resources you found online.
Maybe even just taking things directly
from the Podantic AI documentation,
putting those in the example folder as
well. And I just find that examples are
so so powerful for AI coding assistance.
is even better than just looking at the
documentation or doing web research. But
documentation still is important. So
speaking of that, we've got a section
for that as well. Like here, just to
show you kind of what this looks like, I
call out some of the links that we have
from the official Pantic AI docs for
things like creating agents and
integrating tools. And then the last
section that we have here, which is
actually pretty important, is just a
place for you to put any other kinds of
considerations that you have for your AI
coding assistant, like the way that you
wanted to manage environment variables,
for example. And this is also the
perfect place to put any gotchas, as I
like to call them. Like when you've used
AI coding assistance to build agents in
the past, for example, what are those
things that it always messes up on? And
this is your place to correct that
behavior because usually when it messes
up on something in one project, it's
probably going to do something like that
in another project. And so just being
able to adapt your prompting and your
context as you learn the kinds of things
that it likes to mess up on. So yeah,
very important to include that in this
section as well. And so with that, I'm
going to go ahead and paste in my full
initial MD that I have for my agent. And
there we go. All right, paste it in. And
I'll have this linked in the description
as well if you want to see like the full
agent that I build from this process,
too. But yeah, I'm just building a
padantic AI agent that has another agent
as a tool because we're going to have
our primary research agent and then an
email draft agent as a sub aent. I'm
going to keep it very simple here with
the tools that I'm giving it as well.
So, I'm going to give our research agent
the ability to search the web with the
Brave API. And then it has a tool to
also delegate all the email related
stuff like drafting emails to my email
sub agent. And so, a rather simple
example just to demonstrate things
rather quickly for you here, but it's
still like more than just a super super
trivial agent. Like you could definitely
take this further to make it like a real
agent you would actually use. And then
for dependencies, we just need the Brave
API key and then everything for Google
O. I have general instructions for the
system prompt that I want for both
agents. I'm keeping the examples the
same because I already curated a really
nice set of Pantic AI agent examples for
us. And then documentation, keeping it
very bare bones. And then my
considerations is kind of everything
that I already had in the base
initial.mmd just because those are the
things that I found it usually messes up
on. Like it doesn't handle environment
variables correctly, for example. So
that is my initial MD. Now I'll just do
CtrlJ to open my terminal back up. And
I'll go into Claude. And now all I need
to do is generate the PRP based on the
initial MD that I created. So it's
slashgenerate pyantic AI PRP. I'll hit
tab to autocomplete. And then the one
argument that we need here. And we can
go into this and see what that looks
like. If I do Ctrl J to close the
terminal again, we have the one argument
which is our feature file. That is our
initial.md. So it takes that. we have
the rest of the context for how it needs
to generate a PRP and validate it. That
is all within the prompt here. And so
going back to my terminal here, I'll
just pass in the relative path to my
initial MD. If I can type right. There
we go. All right. So we got our initial
MD. We'll send this in. And like I said,
if you don't have cloud code, you're not
using slash commands, you can just use
this as a regular prompt. Tell it to
look at this file for its prompt. So
I'll send this in. And now this process
is going to take a good amount of time
because it's going to do a lot of
research and architecting on our behalf,
thinking through step by step what needs
to go into the PRP and then putting it
in there. And then our end result is
we'll have a new PRP in our PRPS folder.
So I will pause and come back once that
is generated. All right, our PRP is now
generated. And the next thing I want to
go through with you is at least at a
high level how we can go in and validate
our PRP. You don't want to trust the AI
coding assistant blindly. Validation is
so important. And so, at least at a high
level, I want to show you what that
looks like. And if you saw my last video
doing the similar process, but for MCP
servers, a lot of this is going to be
pretty similar. But I still want to dive
in and show you what this looks like
specifically for building AI agents with
Pantic AI. And so, we took our base PRP
for Pantic AI. We took our initial MD.
This is the baby of those two things.
And this is what we're going to use to
build our agent. So you got core
principles, what to do and what not to
do for highle instructions. We have
exactly what we're building here with
all the documentation that we need. And
this is a beautiful blend of resources
online, existing examples that we have
in our examples folder. It's going to
load all these things into context when
it first builds our agent. That's
exactly what we want it to do. even
including documentation for things like
Gmail and Brave so it knows how to build
our tools properly as well. AI coding
assistants love to hallucinate the way
that we use these specific APIs when
they don't have access to this
documentation. Now, one thing that this
PRP doesn't have that I wish it did is
the final code structure. And we have
that called out in the base PRP. So
maybe I'd go through and like ask it to
iterate and add that into the PRP. And
so there's definitely going to be some
things where you go through this, you're
like, "Oh, that's not quite right." and
you want to edit it yourself or ask it
to change. Like I said, be a part of the
process here. Validate and iterate on
the PRP before you send it in to execute
it. And so, yeah, it's covering Pantic
AI gotas and general best practices for
using Pantic AI, talking about our
stack. I'm not going to go through
everything in detail here, but like
overall, this is looking pretty good.
And the last thing that I want to cover
here is what are called validation
gates. This is one of my favorite parts
of the PRP framework because you always
want to describe to the AI coding
assistant in the PRP. What do you need
to do to actually validate that your
code is good? And it doesn't mean that
it's guaranteed to be perfect, but
having it do things like write unit
tests and iterate on them until they are
all passing. That kind of thing is just
so so powerful. And in this case here,
let me scroll down to the validation
gates. I don't necessarily need it to
do, you know, like security production
validation and integration testing. So
like this is something I usually end up
cleaning up where it like goes a bit
overboard with validation gates. So just
to show you one example of how I will go
in and change things before I execute
the PRP, but otherwise this is looking
really good. And then it also gives a
confidence score, which another pro tip
on this. What I can do is literally say,
what would it take to get to a 10 out of
10 confidence score? And so it'll ask me
a couple of follow-up questions to then
adjust the PRP further to add anything
that it's not really confident in right
now. So this is just yet another thing
to do um just to get better results once
you go and do the implementation. And so
yeah, it just says that it doesn't quite
understand how to do the Gmail ooth 2
flow right now. And so what I'm going to
do off camera here is go through this
process. I'm going to refine the PRP
completely. Then I'll come back and we
can execute it. All right, our PRP is
now refined. I don't need to show you
everything again. So, we can go ahead
and move on to executing our PRP. So,
when you copy over the template into a
new folder with the copy template Python
script, we take the original readme and
I just rename it here because you also
want your AI coding assistant to produce
a brand new readme for your agent once
you build it. So, I just re renamed this
to readme template. But yeah, this has
all of our instructions that I was
showing you in the GitHub earlier. So,
we filled our initial MD. We generated
our PRP. Now, we can execute it. And so,
the command for that, and actually what
I recommend doing no matter what is
clearing your conversation before you
execute the PRP because you don't want
to have all of the old context left over
from when you were generating it. And
so, I'll just do exit here. Go back into
Claude. You could also do the /clear
command. And then, no matter your AI
coding assistant, you can just start a
new session here. And so then the
command that I'll use now is
slashexecute podantic AI PRP tab to
autocomplete and then I'll pass in the
path to my PRP. So it's PRPS
research email agent CLIMD.
That's just the name that the AI coding
assistant came up with. There we go. All
right. And then I'll do shift tab to
enable autocomplete. And we are off to
the races. All right. Our agent is being
created now. And this process will go
for a good amount of time because we
have such an extensive set of
instructions here and so much context
for it to sift through as well. But man,
the results that we get from this time
and time again just blow me away. And so
yet again, I will pause and come back
once we have the initial version of our
agent created. And there we go. Our
agent is now complete. And I did iterate
two times off camera just to fix a
couple of small things. It wasn't
handling the conversation history quite
right in the CLI and then all of the
tests weren't quite passing. So I wanted
to make sure that was in tip-top shape,
but otherwise this was amazing. It
almost one-shotted the entire agents.
And actually there's two agents here
because we have the one for research and
then the one for emails. And I went
through the code and I validated
everything after as well. And it's
really important to do that to make sure
that it isn't just vibe coding, right?
Like you want to understand what it
outputed here and validate it yourself.
But this all looked really good to me.
And you can view this repo if you want.
I'll have this linked below as well if
you want to see the final result for
yourself. And then I literally just
followed the readme to get everything
set up myself. My environment variables,
the credentials for Gmail, my virtual
environment. I got all that set up. And
so now I can run this in the command
line. So python research email cli.py.
We'll have a very similar demo here to
what I showed at the start of the video.
So, I can just say something simple like
search for the latest on claude code and
send a draft of the findings to and I'll
just do my own email here. It doesn't
really matter for a simple demo. So,
it's going to use the Brave API first.
There we go. Search in the web. And then
at some point, Yep, there we go. It's
going to hand off to my email sub agent
now to create that draft for me. And it
takes a little bit because it's going to
craft the full email here. But in a
second, it'll tell us that it has
drafted the email. There we go. All
right. Perfect. So, yeah. Now, I'm going
to refresh my drafts on my other monitor
here. All right. Nice. Yep. I'll bring
it over. There we go. Take a look at
this. Latest updates on cloud code to
myself. And yeah, I mean, the email
might be a little corny here. You can
definitely work on the system prompt to
like make it so that this actually
sounds like what you want it to sound
like. And really, there's probably a lot
of room to continue to iterate on this
agent here. This is just more of a
demonstration I wanted to have for you
for starting with the PRP framework to
begin a new project. You can definitely
take this a lot further as well. So, I
will have links in the description to
the Pantic AI template. You got the read
me to go through the same process
yourself. I'll even link to this agent
that I created as well, so you can take
a look at the final results if you want.
That is everything that I've got now for
context engineering the PRP framework
for paidantic AI agents. I hope that you
found this really valuable really taking
this and building any AI agent that you
want with it and certainly a lot more
templates coming out for other use cases
soon as well. So stay tuned for that. If
you appreciated this content, you're
looking forward to more things with AI
coding and AI agents, I'd really
appreciate a like and a subscribe. And
with that, I will see you in the next